I want you guys to imagine that you're a soldier
أريدكم أن تتخيلوا بأنكم جنود
running through the battlefield.
تجرون في ساحة المعركة
Now, you're shot in the leg with a bullet,
الآن، قد أصبتم بطلق ناري في الساق،
which severs your femoral artery.
أدى إلى قطع شريان الفخذ.
Now, this bleed is extremely traumatic
هذا النزيف رضحي للغاية
and can kill you in less than three minutes.
ويمكنه قتلك في أقلّ من ثلاث دقائق.
Unfortunately, by the time that a medic
لسوء الحظ، بحلول الوقت الذي يحتاجه المسعف
actually gets to you,
للوصول إليك،
what the medic has on his or her belt
ما لدى المسعف في جعبته
can take five minutes or more,
يمكن أن يستغرق خمس دقائق أو أكثر،
with the application of pressure, to stop that type of bleed.
مع تطبيق الضغط لإيقاف هذا النوع من النزيف.
Now, this problem is not only a huge problem
هذه المشكله ليست فقط مشكلة خطيرة
for the military, but it's also a huge problem
للقوات المسلحة، لكنها مشكلة خطيرة
that's epidemic throughout the entire medical field,
سائدة في الحقل الطبي بأكمله،
which is how do we actually look at wounds
وهي كيف ننظر حقًا إلى الجروح
and how do we stop them quickly
وكيف نوقف نريفهم بسرعة
in a way that can work with the body?
بطريقة تتماشى مع الجسد؟
So now, what I've been working on for the last four years
إذًا والآن، ما قد عملت عليه خلال الأربعة أعوام الماضية
is to develop smart biomaterials,
هو تطوير مواد بيولوجية ذكية،
which are actually materials that will work
هي حقيقةً مواد ستتجاوب
with the body, helping it to heal
مع الجسم، وتساعده على الشفاء
and helping it to allow the wounds to heal normally.
وتساعده أيضًا ليسمح للجرح بالشفاء بشكل طبيعي.
So now, before we do this, we have to take a much closer look
حسنًا، قبل أن نقوم بذلك، علينا أن ننظر بكثب إلى
at actually how does the body work.
كيفية عمل الجسم الفعلية.
So now, everybody here knows
الجميع هنا يعلم
that the body is made up of cells.
أن الجسم مصنوع من الخلايا.
So the cell is the most basic unit of life.
إذًا الخلية هي الوحدة الأساسية للحياة.
But not many people know what else.
ولكن ليس الكثير من الناس يعرفون أكثر.
But it actually turns out that your cells
تبيّن بالفعل أن خلاياكم
sit in this mesh of complicated fibers,
تتموضع في هذه الشبكة من الألياف المعقدة،
proteins and sugars
والبروتينات والسكريات
known as the extracellular matrix.
المعروفة باسم "مصفوفة خارج الخلية"
So now, the ECM
هذه المصفوفة
is actually this mesh that holds the cells in place,
هي الشبكة التي تثبّت الخلايا في مكانها،
provides structure for your tissues,
توفّر الهيكل لأنسجتك،
but it also gives the cells a home.
ولكنها أيضًا توفّر المنزل للخلايا.
It allows them to feel what they're doing,
تسمح لهم بالإحساس بما يقومون به،
where they are, and tells them
وبمكانهم وتخبرهم
how to act and how to behave.
كيفية العمل وكيفية التصرف.
And it actually turns out that the extracellular matrix
وتبيّن بالفعل بأنّ مصفوفة خارح الخلية
is different from every single part of the body.
مختلفة عن كل جزء مستقلّ من الجسم
So the ECM in my skin
لذا إن المصفوفة في بشرتي
is different than the ECM in my liver,
مختلفة عن تلك التي في كبدي،
and the ECM in different parts of the same organ
والمصفوفة في أجزاء مختلفة من العضو الواحد
actually vary, so it's very difficult
تختلف في الواقع، لذلك من الصعب
to be able to have a product
أن يكون هناك منتج
that will react to the local extracellular matrix,
من شأنه أن يستجيب لمصفوفة خارج الخلية الموضعية،
which is exactly what we're trying to do.
والذي يماثل ما نقوم به تمامًا.
So now, for example, think of the rainforest.
على سبيل، المثال فكروا بالغابات المطيرة.
You have the canopy, you have the understory,
لديك الغطاء وماتحته،
and you have the forest floor.
ولديك أرض الغابة.
Now, all of these parts of the forest
كل أجزاء الغابة تلك
are made up of different plants,
تتكوّن من نباتات مختلفة،
and different animals call them home.
وتعتبر موطنًا لحيوانات مختلفة.
So just like that, the extracellular matrix
لذلك تعتبر مصفوفة خارج الخلية
is incredibly diverse in three dimensions.
متنوعة للغاية في أبعادها الثلاثة.
On top of that, the extracellular matrix
وعلاوة على ذلك فإنّ هذه المصفوفة
is responsible for all wound healing,
مسؤولة عن التئام الجروح،
so if you imagine cutting the body,
لذلك إذا تصورت حدوث قطع في الجسم،
you actually have to rebuild
عليك فعليًا أن تقوم بإعادة بناء
this very complex ECM
هذه المصفوقة المعقدة
in order to get it to form again,
من أجل أن تتشكّل من جديد،
and a scar, in fact, is actually
والندبة في حقيقة الأمر
poorly formed extracellular matrix.
ما هي إلّا شكل سيء من المصفوفة.
So now, behind me is an animation
الآن، تظهر ورائي رسوم متحركة
of the extracellular matrix.
عن مصفوفة خارج الخلية.
So as you see, your cells sit in this complicated mesh
كما ترون تتموضع خلاياكم في هذه الشبكة المعقدة
and as you move throughout the tissue,
وأثناء تنقلنا في هذا النسيج،
the extracellular matrix changes.
تتغيّر هذه المصفوفة.
So now every other piece of technology on the market
حتى الآن كل مواد التكنولوجيا الأخرى المتوفرة في السوق
can only manage a two- dimensional approximation
يمكنها أن تتدبر تقريب ثنائي الأبعاد فقط
of the extracellular matrix,
لمصفوفة خارج الخلية،
which means that it doesn't fit in
هذا يعني أنها لا تتلاءم
with the tissue itself.
مع النسيج بحدّ ذاته.
So when I was a freshman at NYU,
عندما كنت مستجد في جامعة نيويورك،
what I discovered was you could actually take
اكتشفت أنه بالإمكان أخذ
small pieces of plant-derived polymers
قطع صغيرة من المركبات الكيميائية المشتقة من النباتات
and reassemble them onto the wound.
وإعادة تجميعها على الجرح.
So if you have a bleeding wound like the one behind me,
فلو أصبت بجرح ينزف مثل الذي يظهر خلفي،
you can actually put our material onto this,
يكمنك وضع مادتنا عليه،
and just like Lego blocks,
وتمامًا مثل قطع الليجو،
it'll reassemble into the local tissue.
ستعيد تجميع الأنسجة الأصلية.
So that means if you put it onto liver,
هذا يعني أنّه بوضعها على الكبد،
it turns into something that looks like liver,
تتحول إلى شيء يشبه الكبد،
and if you put it onto skin,
وإذا وضعت على الجلد،
it turns into something that looks just like skin.
تتحوّل إلى شيء يبدو مثل الجلد.
So when you put the gel on,
لذا عند وضع الهلام،
it actually reassembles into this local tissue.
فإنه يعيد تجميع النسيج الموضعي فعلًا.
So now, this has a whole bunch of applications,
هذا لديه مجموعة كاملة من التطبيقات،
but basically the idea is, wherever you put this product,
لكن في الأساس فإن الفكرة هي أنه أينما وضع هذا المنتج،
you're able to reassemble into it immediately.
تتمكن من إعادة تجميعه على الفور.
Now, this is a simulated arterial bleed —
الآن هذه محاكاة لنزيف شرياني ـــ
blood warning —
إنذار بوجود دماء ـــ
at twice human artery pressure.
عند تطبيق ضعفي الضغط الشرياني البشري.
and like I said before, would actually take
وكما ذكرت من قبل، سيستغرق هذا النزيف
five minutes or more with pressure
خمس دقائق أو أكثر من الضغط
to be able to stop.
لتتمكن من إيقافه.
Now, in the time that it takes me to introduce the bleed itself,
في الوقت الذي نتعرف فيه على نوع النزيف،
our material is able to stop that bleed,
تتمكّن مادتنا من إيقافه،
and it's because it actually goes on and works
وذلك لأنها تدخل وتعمل
with the body to heal,
مع الجسم من أجل الشفاء،
so it reassembles into this piece of meat,
لذا هي تعيد التجمّع داخل قطعة اللحم هذه،
and then the blood actually recognizes
ثم يدرك الدم فعليًا
that that's happening, and produces fibrin,
بما يحدث فينتج الفايبرين،
producing a very fast clot in less than 10 seconds.
مكونًا جلطة سريعة جدًا في أقل من عشر ثوان.
So now this technology — Thank you.
هذه التكنولوجيا ـــ أشكركم
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
So now this technology, by January, will be in the hands of veterinarians,
هذه التكنولوجيا، وبحلول يناير، ستكون متوفرة لدى الأطباء البيطريين
and we're working very diligently to try to get it into the hands of doctors,
ونحن نعمل بجد للغاية في محاولة لتصبح متوفرة بأيدي الأطباء،
hopefully within the next year.
نأمل ذلك في غضون السنة القادمة.
But really, once again, I want you guys to imagine
حقيقةَ، ومرة أخرى أريدكم أن تتخيلوا
that you are a soldier running through a battlefield.
بأنكم جنود تجرون في أرض المعركة.
Now, you get hit in the leg with a bullet,
وقد أصبتم بطلق ناري في الساق،
and instead of bleeding out in three minutes,
وبدلًا من أن تنزفوا لآخر قطرة خلال ثلاث دقائق،
you pull a small pack of gel out of your belt,
تسحبون حزمة صغيرة من الهلام من حزامكم،
and with the press of a button,
وبالضغط على زرّ واحد،
you're able to stop your own bleed
ستتمكنون من إيقاف نزيفكم
and you're on your way to recovery.
وتصبحون على طريق التعافي.
Thank you very much.
أشكركم جزيل الشكر.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)